Guide to the Samuel Francis Smith Collection, 1835-1957
Department of Special Collections
Samuel Francis Smith Collection,
1835-1957
Special Collections M0219
Smith, Samuel Francis.
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Elinor C. Bramhall Estate, 1972.
Scope and Content
The S. F. Smith Collection contains papers dealing with S. F. Smith and his descendents and the Bramhall family. It contains photographs, newspaper articles dealing with Smith and the writing of My Country, `Tis of Thee, pamphlets, correspondence to and from Smith and to and from the Bramhall family, holograph biographies of Civil War officers and a large framed copy of My Country, `Tis of Thee by Smith.
Container List
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - a) BW photo, 1 3/4" X 2 3/8" of woman with A. inscription on back To Emma... from [?] G.
  - b) 2 BW photos 6 1/4" X 4 1/8" 1 of Dr. David Appleton White Smith in his study, 1 of a couple in front of a large tropical style house.
  - c) BW photo, 4 1/2" X 3 5/8" of 2 couples [missionaries?] in tropics.
  - d) BW photograph, 4 1/2" X 3 1/4", of group in tropics.
  - e) BW photo, 2 1/2" X 4 1/2", of three people in a study.
  - f) BW photo, 4 1/2" X 6 1/2", portrait of H. W. Longfellow.
  - g) BW photo, 4 1/2" X 6 1/2", portrait of O. W. Holmes.
  - h) BW photo, 4 1/2" X 6 1/2", portrait of J. G. Whittier, 1872.
  - i) BW photo, 4 1/2" X 6 1/2", portrait of D. E. Farragut, signed.
  - j) BW photo, 4 1/8" X 5 7/8", Smith home.
  - k) BW photo, 4 1/2" X 6 1/2", 4 portraits of Smith, 3 signed.
  - l) BW photo, 3" X 6 1/2", original of America mounted on 7" X 9" heavy board.
- Newspaper articles giving detailed historical background on S. F. Smith and the writing of America: (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 3/28/1894 Leslie's Weekly
  - 10/11/08 L. A. Times Illustrated Weekly
  - 1/19/11 The Christian Endeavor World
  - 1/21/30 Boston Post
  - 1/27/30 Boston Traveler
  - 6/32 Missions
  - 7/37 Etude
  - 11/24/38 San Juan Record
  - 12/22/40 Boston Herald
  - 1/23/53 N. Y. Times
  - [?]/53Reader's Digest (condensation of N. Y. Times)
  - 6/30/57 Boston Sunday Globe
  - 11/3/57 Boston Sunday Globe
  - 6/18[09?] N. Y. Times
  - 8/6/[?] Chicago Sunday Tribune
  - ND[?] - A Boy's Hunt for Big Game
  - ND The Household
  - NDPhoto of S. F. Smith with words America
- Newspaper articles on relatives of S. F. Smith: (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 7/15/02The Daily News - wedding of Emma Eugenia Smith
  - 7/15/[02][?] - same subject as above.
  - 5/19/03Erie Daily Times - death of E. H. Mack, Sr.
  - 2/12/48Erie Daily Times - Boston Store ad honoring its employees
  - 1/15/53San Juan Record - Honoring Mrs. R. N. Bramhall, a Fair Oaks pioneer.
- Newspaper articles on Civil War (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 6/13/1862[ N. Y. Tribune?]
  - 8/5/1862[ N. Y. Tribune?]
  - 8/19/1862 N. Y. Tribune
  - 9/18/1862[ N. Y. Tribune?]
- 2 pamphlets: (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - a) My Country, `Tis of Thee and the Latest Poems of Rev. Samuel Francis Smith, D. D., by Rev. George C. Lorimer, D. D. - 1896.
  - b) The Shrine of `America' and the Story of the Lone Star.
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - a) Envelope with calling card of Julius Brill and 4 cut out heads.
  - b) Calling card - Miss Emma E. Smith
  - c) Pamphlet - Daniel Appleton White Smith by Emma W. Marshall and Harry J. Marshall.
  - d) 2 maps - one of Sacramento County and one of portion of Fair Oaks and Olive Park Tracts.
  - e) 5 pencil sketches of scenes, or patters.
  - f) Cloth tract issued by Youn Men's Association.
  - g) 7 printed pictures - 2 in color.
- Correspondence and documents from and to S. F. Smith: (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 4/29/1874Marriage certificate, E. U. Smith to Eugenia Mack.
  - 4/28/1874Marriage license, E. U. Smith to E. Mack.
  - 12/11/1894ALS, 8vo., 4 pgs., S. F. Smith to Gov. Mack.
  - NDA. poem by S. F. Smith for Ewing and Gerrie.
- Correspondence to and from the Bramhall family: (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 10/15/1835A. marriage certificate of Charles U. Bramhall to Eliza hogeborn by J. Berger.
  - 8/5/1845ALS Caroline E. Smith to Eliza Bramhall.
  - 12/9/1845ALS Tobias L. Hogeborn to Charles H. Bramhall.
  - 11/22/1846ALS Mary D. Tabor to Eliza [Bramhall]
  - 4/12/1857E. F. Howland to Eliza [Bramhall]
  - 5/5/1860Nellie [?] to Sister [?]
  - 5/11/1861ANS A. G. Weld to [Charles] Bramhall
  - 1/26/1862ALS A. R. Barlow to Charles Bramhall
  - 3/2/1863ALS Abby Floss [?] to Eliza Bramhall
  - 3/31/1863ANS Abby Floss to [?] Bramhall
  - 3/31/1863ALS Ann Rebecca [?] to Charles H. Bramhall
  - 8/4/1863Proclamation signed by Maj. Gen. Schenk
  - 5/28/1866ANS Darin D. P[?] to F. J. B. [?]
  - 10/5/1878ALS Susan [?] to Cousin [?]
  - NDALS H. N. Bramhall to Eliza Marshall
  - NDA. poem - The Vision of St. Valentine's Eve
  - NDA. essay - Elinor Fields, New of Marriage
  - NDA. Verses by Elinor Fields composed for her amusement
  - NDANS C. Roosevelt to [Charles] Bramhall
  - NDALS Ernest Blum to Mrs. Bramhall
  - NDALS Ernest Blum to [Mrs. Bramhall]
  - NDALS Ernest Blum to Charles H. Bramhall
- Biographies of Officers in the Civil War: (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - List of Military Souvenirs, Vol. 2.
  - C. C. Auger
  - Jonas G. Blunt
  - T. Wylie Crawford
  - George L. Hartsuff
  - O. O. Howard
  - John J. Peck
  - Alfred Pleasanton
  - W. D. Porter
  - James B. Richett
  - L. H. Rousseau
  - Robert C. Schenk
  - H. W. Slocum
  - George Stoneman
- A & B: Original manuscript and carbon copy of S. F. Smith by Mrs. Robert N. Bramhall - 10/12/38 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- C: 6th level picture bin # 163: framed copy in S. F. Smith's handwriting of America oversize (Box 1, Folder 10)